When you’ve finished your studies at school and college, do you feel like a well-earned rest?
当你完成中学和专科的学业后，是否想好好休息一下？
If you’re about to embark on a course at university, you’ll want to recharge your batteries, let your hair down and have some fun.
如果你即将开启大学课程，想必会想养精蓄锐、放松身心，享受一段欢乐时光。
But how long should you do that for?
但这样的时光该持续多久呢？
Now the idea of taking a year off before you move into further education seems to be the thing to do.
如今，在升入高等教育之前先休学一年（即间隔年），似乎已成为一种潮流。
A year off – also called a gap year – is not a new concept, but there’s now a focus on making the most of this break from academic life.
休学一年——也被称为间隔年——并不是什么新概念，但现在人们更注重充分利用这段脱离学术生活的假期。
Long gone are the days of just hanging out on a beach or backpacking round the world.
仅仅是在海滩休闲或环球背包旅行的日子早已过去。
While that is still an option, a gap year is now more about gaining skills that will help you in later life.
虽然这些仍是可选方案，但如今的间隔年更侧重于获取对未来生活有益的技能。
The BBC’s Smart Consumer podcast spoke to a student called Meg, who said “I just always had in the back of my mind I'd spend a year doing something productive and something that would just be good fun.”
英国广播公司《精明消费者》播客采访了一位名叫梅格的学生，她说：“我心底深处一直在想，要花一年时间做些有意义且有趣的事。”
Doing something productive is exactly what students are being encouraged to do because doing more purposeful things like work experience or charity work helps them acquire skills to use when competing for a place at university.
鼓励学生们做些有意义的事，因为参与工作实习、慈善活动等更具目的性的项目，能帮助他们获得申请大学时所需的技能。
It looks good on their CV and ultimately makes them more employable.
这会让他们的个人简历更具吸引力，最终提升就业竞争力。
Chris Rea is a Higher Education Services Manager from organisation, Prospects. He told the BBC that he thinks “the experience of the gap year has become actually much more practical, partly to do with university participation increasing, but also because of the demands on developing skills, specifically employability skills.”
英国职业规划机构Prospects的高等教育服务经理克里斯·雷向英国广播公司表示：“间隔年的经历实际上变得更加实用，一方面是因为上大学的人数增多，另一方面是因为社会对技能培养的需求，尤其是就业技能。”
While the benefits of taking a gap year are clear to see, some students worry they can’t afford it.
尽管间隔年的好处显而易见，但有些学生担心自己负担不起。
Another student, Tom, told the BBC that to him, a gap year was an ‘alien concept’.
另一位学生汤姆告诉英国广播公司，对他来说，间隔年是一个“陌生的概念”。
He said “it would have been far too expensive and it's not something that I would have been able to rely on my parents or family members for.”
他说：“这实在太贵了，我也不能依赖父母或家人来承担这笔费用。”
But some experts say that it needn’t burn a hole in your pocket; you don’t need to travel far and you can even earn money by doing paid work.
但一些专家表示，间隔年并不需要花费巨资；你不必远行，甚至可以通过有偿工作赚取收入。
For those who do have the funds, a combination of working, volunteering and travelling is undoubtedly an amazing opportunity.
对于那些有经济能力的人来说，将工作、志愿服务和旅行结合起来的间隔年无疑是一次绝佳的机会。
It increases confidence and independence, gives you a chance to learn new crafts, and gives you time to contemplate whether university is right for you.
它能增强你的自信心和独立性，让你有机会学习新技能，并有时间思考大学是否真的适合自己。